thecriticsguide.com 2019-06-11

# Discover the world's finest luxury hotels and restaurants

The Critics Guide takes security and privacy seriously:  

  * We keep to a minimum the amount of information we hold about you.
  * We use your data to respond to your enquiries about our services (the lawful basis for this is “Legitimate Interest”) and to provide our services to you (the lawful basis for this is “Contract”).
  * We delete your data when it is no longer needed.
  * We apply appropriate security mechanisms to protect your personal data.

For the definition of terms used within this Privacy Policy refer to the [ICO website](https://ico.org.uk/) or look at the General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR”). We suggest you start with the ICO website.

We are happy to answer any questions you have about this Privacy Policy. Contact us via email privacy@thecriticsguide.com

### What personal data do we hold and why?

Your name and contact information, provided by you, will be used to respond to your enquiries, requests for further information, and to communicate with you during the provision of our services to you.

As our client we will also hold information about your business activities as part of the delivery of our services. 

The Critics Guide website uses only standard fixed 'cookies'. Further information about cookies is provided below in our cookie policy.

### Whom do we share it with?

All third parties we use - including those who provide email and storage solutions used in our day to day work - are selected for, and monitored on, how they meet the requirements of current UK data protection legislation and the requirements of GDPR. 

Where this includes storage or processing of information outside of the European Ecomonic Area (EEA), we include checks to ensure that compliance with the appropriate frameworks for exchange of personal data (such as the EU-US Privacy Shield) is in place.

Exemptions to the above are where we are asked to provide information as a result of a court order or to recover monies due.

We do not share nor sell your personal data to anyone else.

### Security

We are committed to ensuring that your information is secure. In order to prevent unauthorised access or disclosure, we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online. 

### Links to other websites

Our website may contain links to other websites of interest. However, once you have used these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this privacy statement. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.

### How long do we store your data for?

We will store your personal information for a maximum of two years after your last communication with us, or from the date of completion of our services, whichever is the latest. If you wish to stop hearing from us prior to that time then email privacy@thecriticsguide.com.

If you are a sole trader or partnership, financial transactions between us might include some personal data. We are required to keep this information for the current financial year plus an additional six years.

Whilst we store your information we store it securely to prevent unauthorised use.

### How to change information or contact us about anything concerning our use of your personal data

If there are any changes in your details that we need to reflect, you need to check the accuracy of the details that we hold about you, or if you have any other questions about this Privacy Policy, email privacy@thecriticsguide.com.

Should you feel that you need to complain about how we are handling your personal data, email privacy@thecriticsguide.com or use the 'Contact' form on our website. Your ultimate point of contact for all data protection matters in the UK is the Information Commissionerâ€™s Office. See the Contact us page on the ICO website.

### What is this privacy notice changes?

If changes to The Critics Guide Data Protection Policy (and hence this Privacy Policy) include any significantly different use of your personal data, we will let you know and give you the option to agree to the new use.

* * *

### Cookie Policy

You're seeing this because you clicked on a page that uses cookies. Under a new EU Directive, effective 26 May 2012, site owners now need permission to use cookies. We are using this page to fully comply with that Directive.

The EU cookie law is a piece of privacy legislation that seeks to improve personal privacy on the internet. It was originally adopted by other EU countries in 2011, but the UK was given a year to comply after it updated its Privacy and Electronic Communications Regulations, which brought the directive in to UK law.

The law now requires websites to gain consent from visitors to store or receive any information on a computer, or any other web-enabled device. The intent is to make you aware that we use cookies and to give you the option to control their use.

### What is a Cookie?

Cookies are small files that contain information about particular websites you visit. Our cookie remembers the site, the time and date you last visited and any login information you may use. They also record any preferences you select while on the site.

The idea of the cookie is to enhance the browsing experience by taking care of all the little details for you when your revisit this site.

Sites that have advertising use them to allow rotation of adverts. They read the cookies, see where you have surfed and find adverts pertinent to your tastes.

### How Do Cookies Affect My Browsing?

Up until now, cookies have been such an inherent part of web browsing that many sites depend on them. Refusing cookies can result is a loss of some functionality and some services on websites simply won't work.

This isn't blackmail to force you to accept cookies, it's just how the web works.

We do not collect any private information through using cookies. We only use them to enhance your experience on this site and to remember your site preferences, nothing else!

You can find out about how we use cookies below. It will tell you what types of cookies we use and how they provide you with the services on the site.

You now have the choice whether or not to allow this website to use cookies. As mentioned, you should be aware that not using cookies may result a reduction of functionality and/or the loss of some site tools.

### More Info

We have surveyed our website and found we use the following cookies.

__utma  
__utmb  
__utmc  
__utmz

PHP Session ID  
PHPSESSID 

**Google Analytics Cookies**  
Google Analytics is a website monitoring tool that allows users to see volumes of website visitors, their source, and to analyse how the content of their website is viewed and navigated. This in turn allows optimisation of the content and pages on the marketing programs that drive traffic to the website. Google Analytics does not store any personal information about website visitors, but does use persistent cookies to identify repeat visitors. You may universally opt-out of all Google Analytics tracking used by all websites by visiting the following url [**https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout**](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout)

For information about opting out of Rakuten Marketing and ad serving partners please visit **<https://rakutenmarketing.com/en-uk/legal-notices/website-privacy-policy>**

Last updated: May 25, 2018.
